Cedric.
塞多利克
Brother. How unusual.
王兄 真是稀客
The empress dowager summoned me.
王太后找我来的
Grandmother? Please be careful.
祖母找王兄 那么请小心吧
Sorry for making you worried all the time.
抱歉 我总是让你担心了
Worried about you?
我担心王兄
Aren't we siblings fighting to become the emperor?
我们是为了成为国王 而互相竞争的兄弟吧
It's not us who are fighting to become the emperor, isn't it?
竞争王位的人 不是我和你吧
It's me and you, Brother.
是我和王兄
I will become the emperor in the end.
最后 我会成为国王
For your fiancee's sake?
为了你的未婚妻吗
Yes. Isn't that Aileen's wish as well? That is why you wanted to become the emperor.
对 爱琳也希望如此 所以王兄才想当国王吧
Let me give you some advice.
我给你个忠告
A woman gets tired quickly when a man always obeys her.
女人对于言听计从的男人 很快就腻了
Brother. Lilia seems to be plotting something.
王兄 莉莉安似乎有所企图
Be careful.
请留意
That's all I can tell you.
我只能告诉你这些
I'M THE VILLAINESS, SO I'M TAMING THE FINAL BOSS!
《因为是反派大小姐》 《所以养了魔王》
THE VILLAINESS IS BEST FORGOTTEN
(忘记反派大小姐吧)
Show me your other merchandise.
让我看看其他商品吧
How much for that?
价格多少
I wondered where you were taking us.
我还想说要带我们去哪
Turns out it was an underground auction.
没想到是地下拍卖会
Is it true that there's going to be a Demon Snuff transaction?
听说有交易魔香 是真的吗
That's right. They are also selling demons as well.
没错 似乎也有在交易魔物
If something happens, Auguste will take action as a member of the Holy Knights.
如果有什么万一 奥古斯特以圣骑士团的身份行动
Does Master Claude know about this?
库洛德大人知道这件事吗
Well...
这个嘛…
You shouldn't hide from the Demon King, right?
不能瞒着魔王大人吧
You just angered him recently.
之前才惹他生气的
What are you talking about? Master Claude has always been gentle to me.
你在说什么呢 库洛德大人总是对我很温柔哦
Anyway, let the operation commence.
总之 作战开始
Split into two groups and investigate.
分两路调查
I'm not used to places like this.
我真不习惯这种场合
You'll gain experience once a bad woman lies to you for one night.
只要被坏女人骗 一个晚上就能吸取到经验值
I'm already...
我已经被…
The demons have escaped!
魔物逃走了
It must be James. Now's the time.
是赛姆斯他们 趁现在
Auguste, keep watch over the corridor. If anything unusual happens...
奥古斯特 看着走廊 有异状就立刻…
Aili!
艾里
Magic?
魔法
Don't worry. I'm on your side.
放心吧 我是你们的同伴
Nice to meet you. Miss Aileen Lauren Dautriche.
初次见面 爱琳 罗伦 多德勒小姐
You are a mage.
你是…魔导士
Yes. It might not be right
是的 虽然这并不合规矩
but I came here to meet with the Demon King.
但我是为了见魔王大人一面 才来此的
There's an intruder! Check the situation inside!
有人入侵 确认里面状况
Here.
给你
This way, please.
这边请
No. We haven't found any evidence yet.
不行 我们还没找到证据
I have the guest list.
我已经拿到宾客名单了
Incredible.
真了不起
I'll consider letting you meet Master Claude in exchange for that.
我考虑让你见库洛德大人 作为交涉条件
Thank you very much.
十分感谢
I found the suspicious people!
找到可疑之人了
All right, hurry up.
好了 动作快
The men have escaped!
男的都逃走了
Find the woman!
把女的找出来
How do we escape?
要如何逃走
I can control the wind. Just jump down.
我会操纵风 请往下跳吧
This is the room! Break in!
就是这个房间 快破门进去
Bring an axe!
拿斧头过来
Can you tell me your name?
能告诉我你的名字吗
Sorry for not introducing myself.
抱歉 我忘了报上自己的名字
I am Elephas Levi.
我是… 艾雷法斯 雷比
"REGALIA OF SAINTS, DEMONS AND MAIDENS" The final boss of the first game's
(圣与魔与少女的雷加利亚) 是1的外传
spin-off fan disc?
FD的最终大魔王
Aili!
艾里
If you want to take a stroll at night,
若想在夜空中散步
you just have to tell me.
跟我说一声就行了
You are not being honest,
你真的很不老实
my dear Aileen.
我心爱的爱琳
What have you been doing behind my back again?
你瞒着我 又做了什么事
After long consideration,
我深思熟虑了许久
I don't think we need any words between us.
看来我两之间 已不需言语
This is my conclusion.
这是我得到的结论
I think we still need to speak with each other to understand each other better.
可是我认为 为了让我们能更加理解 还是需要言语的…
Seems like your body needs to physically understand how important you are to me.
看来我得让你的身体实际感受 我有多重视你
We aren't married yet! We can't do things like that.
我…我们还没结婚 不能做这种事
Find. I'll ask them to leave.
好 我让他们都退下
That's not the point!
这不是重点
I have something to tell you.
我…我有事要跟你说
What is it?
还有什么事
Someone wants to meet you.
有个人 希望见你一面
A mage. You've picked up something fascinating again.
魔导士… 你又捡了奇特的东西
What is your name?
叫什么名字
I am Elephas Levi.
我是艾雷法斯 雷比
It's an honour to meet you, Your Highness, Crown Prince Claude Jeanne Elmir.
有幸见到库洛德 夏努 艾路梅亚 王太子殿下
Elephas Levi.
艾雷法斯 雷比
A descendant of the Levi tribe of magic grand dukes?
是魔法大公雷比一族的末裔吗
I'm just serving the Elmir Empire at the moment.
如今 是侍奉艾路梅亚王国的身份
As the crown prince, you should know about us.
王太子殿下 应理解我们的立场才是
The Levi tribe.
雷比一族
In the game, they are a rare tribe born with magic.
在游戏中的设定是 出生便拥有魔力的稀有族群
The Elmir Empire thinks their magic is related to the demons
艾路梅亚王国认为 魔力与魔物相通
so they have been treating the mage tribe cruelly.
因此持续残忍对待魔导士族群
20 years ago, the Levi tribe planned to expand their territory.
20年前 雷比一族欲扩大领土
They declared war against the empire and lost.
便与王国宣战 最后却战败
After that, the tribe's children and elders were taken as hostages
之后 该族的幼童与老人被当人质
to force the mages to protect the imperial family.
强迫魔导士在暗中保护王族
You are hoping me
你希望我当上国王后
to give the Levi tribe citizenship of Elmir Empire once I become emperor.
赋予雷比一族 艾路梅亚王国的市民权
Is that so?
是这样吗
Please save my tribe.
请务必拯救我族
That depends on how well you work.
那就得看你工作的成效了
Adding a new subordinate?
又要增加手下了吗
I'm against it.
我反对
The mage might resent the empire.
毕竟魔导士很可能会对王国报仇
It means that he is also a talent that's capable of taking revenge.
反过来说 他是有能力报仇的人材
Isaac.
艾札克
We are hoping for a world where humans and demons coexist.
我们的期望是 人类与魔物共存的世界
It's only natural to save humans who have been treated cruelly.
拯救饱受残忍待遇的人类 也是理所应当
You are not wrong.
话是这么说没错啦…
Allow me to tell you how wonderful Master Claude is.
就由我来告诉你 库洛德大人有多优秀
Of course. I look forward to hearing that.
我…洗耳恭听…
Demon King. I told you before.
魔王大人 我曾说过
Tie her up with a rope.
用绳子绑好她
You are right.
是啊
That's all for tonight.
今晚就讨论到这里吧
Good night. I love you.
晚安 我爱你
Seriously.
讨厌
Teleporting me back forcefully before I'm done with my conversation.
我话还没说完 就强制送我回来
What a relief.
太好了
The final boss this time is my companion from the start.
这次最终大魔王 一开始就是我们的同伴
Compared to the first game, I don't really remember the fan disc's content.
可是跟1比起来 我更记不清楚FD的内容
I should've played the fan disc seriously.
早知道就认真玩FD了
Master Claude who turned into a demon in the first game
我记得 在1里变成魔物的库洛德大人
was in the fan disc
在FD里…
"REGALIA OF SAINTS, DEMONS AND MAIDENS" as another character that can be tamed.
(圣与魔与少女的雷加利亚) 以爱上主角的攻略角色再次登场
But at that time...
不过 那时…
Almond, come out!
杏仁 出来
Belzebuth is also fine!
佩鲁赛博特也行
What? No way...
怎么会 难道…
Miss Aileen, who are you calling?
爱琳小姐 您刚才呼唤谁…
I'm going to find Master Claude.
我要去找库洛德大人
I'll leave the rest to you.
之后就交给你了
You're going out again? It's the middle of the night.
又要去吗 现在是半夜耶
Aileen, the Demon King...
爱琳 魔王大人他…
Demon King. Gone.
魔王大人 不见了
No response!
没有回应
The forest's barrier disappeared.
森林结界消失了
Aileen. Sorry for disturbing you.
爱琳 打扰一下
Master.
老爷
A man stationed in the castle has reported to me.
我安排在王城里的人跟我报告
Master Claude's stomach was stabbed by someone.
听说库洛德大人不知被何人 在腹部上刺了一剑
Demon King!
魔王大人
No way. Not long ago,
不会吧 不久前…
he just told me he loved me.
他才跟我说爱我的…
Thankfully, he is only injured and isn't in a critical situation.
很庆幸 他只是受了点伤 并没有生命危险
However, he seems to have lost his memory.
不过 似乎丧失记忆了
Love is always lost in an instant.
爱 总是在一瞬间消失殆尽
It happened the first time.
第一次是如此…
It happened again the second time.
第二次…也是如此…
SELENA GILBERT CV AYANA TAKETATSU
(塞蕾娜 吉鲁贝尔) (CV 竹达彩奈)
THE HEROINE OF "REGALIA OF SAINTS, DEMONS AND MAIDENS 2"
(圣与魔与少女的雷加利亚2) (中的女主角)
CONSIDERATE, GOOD AT COOKING. BORN INTO A BAD FAMILY.
(善解仁义 料理手艺佳) (出生在环境不好的家庭中)
HAS BEEN HELPING THE FEMALE STUDENTS SINCE SHE ENROLLED IN THE MALE-DOMINATED ACADEMY.
(就读男尊女卑的学园后) (经常帮助女学生)
What's going on?
这是怎么回事
Why can't I meet Master Claude?
为何我不能见库洛德大人
My son, Crown Prince Claude, has lost his memory and magic.
我的儿子 库洛德皇太子 现在失去了记忆和魔力
He is no longer the Demon King.
他已不是魔王
Separating him from the demons and letting him live as a human
让他与魔物划清界线 重新以人类的身份活下去
will be the best opportunity for him to truly become the emperor.
这便是让他成为真正国王的好机会
Your Majesty.
国王陛下
What about Crown Prince's engagement with my daughter?
王太子与我女儿的婚约 该作何打算
We don't intend to cancel it immediately.
我不会要你们立刻解除婚约
I will think of a time and a reason.
我会想好时机和理由
How can you be so reckless?
怎么能如此武断
Claude no longer retains his previous memories.
库洛德现在没有之前的记忆
I hope to give him another chance to reconsider.
我希望给他重新考虑的机会
Now that he's human again, he will no doubt be highly sought after.
而且 他现在变成人类了 应该有不少爱慕之人
You must be Aileen.
你就是爱琳吧
I believe this is our first meeting.
我们好像是初次见面
It's an honour to be remembered, Your Majesty.
能让王太后陛下记得 是我的荣幸
You are a young and pretty lady.
你真是年轻又漂亮的千金小姐
I'm jealous.
真令人羡慕
I heard about the rumours
我虽听过传闻
but is she really past sixty?
但她真的超过60岁了吗
Actually, I plan to host a ball recently.
其实 哀家最近打算 举办一场舞会
Don't you think this is a good opportunity to choose a wife for my cute grandson?
你们不觉得 这是替可爱孙子选妃的好机会吗
I'm impressed by Your Majesty's political talents.
在下对王太后的政治手腕 每次都佩服的五体投地
However, I don't think our family has received an invitation.
不过我们家 似乎没收到邀请函
There must an error with the program.
应该是程序出错了吧
However, wouldn't it be troublesome if I send you the invitation now?
不过 现在送邀请函 只会给你们带来困扰吧
I am still Master Claude's fiancee!
我还是库洛德大人的未婚妻
Cedric and Lilia are doing their best to take care of him.
塞多利克和莉莉安 正尽心尽力地照顾他
There's no need for you to worry.
无须你来担心
Let me meet with him at least!
至少让我见他一面
I want to see for myself whether Master Claude is really fine.
我想确认库洛德大人 是否真的平安无事
How unseemly.
真难看
Shouldn't you back away if you really love him as you claimed?
如果你真的爱他 就应该退出吧
Pardon our intrusion.
打扰陛下与王太后商讨国事
Lilia insists on coming.
莉莉安坚持要过来
Grandmother!
祖母大人
It's a pity for Lady Aileen to break up.
突然要爱琳小姐分手 实在太可怜了
What is this woman plotting?
这女的 到底在想什么
Breaking the engagement when Brother has lost his memory isn't right.
趁着王兄丧失记忆就解除婚约 有失礼数
After all, everyone knows how close she was to Brother.
毕竟她跟王兄感情很好 是众人皆知的事情
Yes. At least invite her to the ball.
就是啊 至少邀请她来舞会
Fine. I will invite her to the ball.
好吧 就邀请她来吧
However, if you meet Claude before the ball,
不过 在此之前若见了库洛德
I'll execute you for disobeying an imperial edict.
哀家就以违背王令的理由 让你人头落地
I wonder what you can do in a single ball.
究竟 仅此一次的舞会 你又能耍什么花样呢
Grandmother, it'll be fine.
祖母大人 没问题的
Miss Aileen is the main character.
爱琳小姐是主角
She won't lose to a scenario like this.
是主角 就不可能输的
Am I right?
对吧
Let's have some more fun.
我们再玩得开心点嘛
Lady Aileen.
爱琳小姐
That's what this is.
原来是这样
Yes, Miss Lilia.
是啊 莉莉安小姐
I'll let you know that it won't happen twice.
我会让你知道 没有第二次
That's the way.
这样才对嘛
I'm looking forward to it.
我很期待哦
It'll be terribly cruel if this is reality.
如果这是现实 那就太残酷了
Poor Miss Aileen.
爱琳小姐真可怜
Lilia, are you sure it's fine to do that?
莉莉安 这么做真的好吗
What are you worried about?
你在担心什么
We still haven't caught the culprit who attacked Brother.
现在还没抓到袭击兄长的犯人
Besides...
而且…
He is worried that his excellent brother will steal me away from him.
他很担心我被他优秀的哥哥抢走
What a petty and boring man.
真是心眼小又无聊的男人
Lord Cedric, you've always been so kind.
塞多利克大人总是这么温柔
A woman gets tired quickly when a man always obeys her.
女人对于言听计从的男人 很快就腻了
Aileen.
爱琳
The Demon King...
魔王…
I'll depend on you to save him.
魔王就拜托你了
Don't worry.
放心吧
I'm the woman who will become the Demon King's wife.
我是 将成为魔王妻子的女人
That must be the place.
就是那里吧
We found this place thanks to Almond.
多亏了杏仁 找到了这里
Seems like it is protected by a sacred barrier.
好像被神圣结界保护了起来
I can break through a barrier like that any time I want.
这种结界 只要我想 随时都能闯进去
Are they looking down on me?
瞧不起我吗
No one will jump down from a cliff usually.
通常 不会有人从悬崖跳下去
Let's go. Please cast your wind magic.
走吧 拜托你施展风之魔法
I'll break through the barrier with the power of the Holy Sword.
我会用圣剑的力量穿过结界
Are you sure that's a good idea?
这样真的好吗
You'll be executed if you are discovered.
被发现的话会被处以极刑
My resolve is firm.
我已经做好觉悟了
Got it.
我知道了
Give me your hand.
手给我
(Spell)
(咒语)
Holy Sword.
圣剑
Incredible. You are using the sword well.
真厉害 圣剑的力量运用自如
That's not true.
也不能这么说
Sometimes, it won't listen to me.
有时候 它也不会听我的指示
Miss Aileen. Are you all right?
爱琳小姐 没事吧
I'm fine.
我没事
I feel like the Holy Sword has had a mind of its own recently.
我觉得最近 圣剑好像有自我意识…
Lord Cedric.
塞多利克大人
You are here to see Brother, right?
反正你是来见王兄的吧
Follow me.
跟我来
Brother's bedroom is inside.
里面那间就是王兄的寝室
You can do anything you want.
之后就随便你吧
What's going on with you today?
今天是吹什么风吗
All right. Just go inside.
好了 快点进去
I won't alert you if the patrol comes around.
如果有人来巡逻 我可不会告诉你哦
Elephas, wait for me here.
艾雷法斯 你在这里等我
Master Claude...
库洛德大人
He's still alive.
还活着…
What a relief. Nothing else matters as long as you are fine.
太好了 只要你还活着 怎样都无所谓
Lilia...
莉莉安…
Who are you?
你是谁啊
Do you really not remember me?
你真的不记得我了…
It can be helped.
不过 这也是没办法的事
I understand.
我知道了
Please marry me.
那么 请跟我结婚吧
What are you talking about?
你在说什么
If you agree, you'll be able to live a happy and comfortable life with me in the future.
只要答应我 我就能让你过着 幸福又舒适的未来生活
Muster your courage and take that leap of faith.
鼓起勇气 向前跨步吧
Even if I've lost my memory,
就算我丧失记忆了
I won't be so foolish as to marry a person whom I don't know her name.
我也不会傻到 跟不知道名字的陌生人结婚
That was rude of me.
那真是失礼了
I am Aileen Lauren Dautriche,
我是爱琳 罗伦 多德勒
your fiancee, Master Claude.
是库洛德大人 你的未婚妻
Are you Aileen?
你就是爱琳
I'm sorry. I don't want to get involved with you.
不好意思 我不想跟你扯上关系
How can you be so cold?
为何这么冷漠
I don't want to go back to being the Demon King.
我不想回去当魔王
It'll cause the empire a lot of trouble if the crown prince is the Demon King.
皇太子是魔王 会给国家带来多大的负担
Lilia and the rest saved me. I don't want their efforts to go to waste.
莉莉安他们救了我 我不想让他们的辛苦白费
Master Claude.
库洛德大人
So, please cancel our engagement...
所以 请你接受取消婚约的事
Please allow me to neglect your request.
请容我忽视你的请求
I would've cut you if I didn't love you.
若不是我爱你 我早就砍下去了
You love me?
你…爱我
Yes. I wouldn't have risked my life just to meet you otherwise.
是啊 否则我不会赌上性命 来见你一面
What's going on?
这是怎么回事
Meeting Master Claude meant that I'd disobeyed the imperial edict
只要我见了库洛德大人 就会因违反国王命令
and will be executed.
而人头落地
Just go back then.
那你就快点回去
I also think that it's a nuisance.
我也觉得…很困扰
You are still just as kind as you were before.
你还是跟之前一样温柔
I'm glad that you're safe.
太好了 你平安无事
As long as you're alive, I will confess my love to you as many times as possible.
只要你还活着 要我对你示爱几次都没问题
Go away.
走开
A woman shouldn't simply hug a man.
女生不可以随随便便抱男人
I see.
原来如此
You've become pure once you are no longer the Demon King.
不是魔王之后 就变得这么纯情
I really want to take you back right now.
我好想把你带回家哦
I told you not to do that!
我说了 你不要这样
-What should I do? This is fun! -Let me go!
-怎么办 好好玩 -快放开我
Excuse me.
不好意思
The patrols will be coming.
巡逻的人要过来了
There's no choice.
没办法
Master Claude, I will return.
库洛德大人 我还会再来的
You should stop coming here.
你不要再来了…
Sorry for this.
不好意思
What are you doing?
你干什么
A souvenir. I'll take good care of them.
这是土产 我会好好珍惜的
One last thing.
最后还有一件事
Master Claude, you mustn't have an affair.
库洛德大人 不可以搞外遇哦
Affair?
外遇
They should've advised you to choose a new fiancee.
他们应该会劝你选新的未婚妻
What fiancee?
什么未婚妻
I don't even know if I'm fit to become the crown prince.
我现在都还不知道 能不能胜任担任王太子
I have no time to...
没心思去想…
What are you doing?
你干嘛
This is the Master Claude I love.
这样才是我爱的库洛德大人
I will win over your heart no matter how many times it takes me.
我不管花多少次 我都会夺走你的心
What's going on with that girl?
那女的…是怎样
She is my fiancee?
她就是 我的未婚妻
If I fall in love with her again and again,
若我爱上她许多次
doesn't it mean that's fate?
不就代表 这是命运的安排吗